<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Jake Craige Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://jakecraige.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jakecraige.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-14T18:33:01-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://jakecraige.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jake Craige]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[james.craige@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[So you've heard of Vim?]]></title>
    <link href="http://jakecraige.github.io/blog/2013/08/14/so-youve-heard-of-vim/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-14T18:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jakecraige.github.io/blog/2013/08/14/so-youve-heard-of-vim</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m sure the majority of developers out there have heard of Vim. I&rsquo;m also sure
that most of you are frightened by it. <em>No offense</em>. I suppose you have good
reasons for that.</p>

<h3>Let&rsquo;s recreate the first time you encountered vim..</h3>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='&#8220;THIS EDITOR SUCKS&#8221; you say to yourself.'>
You get access to your first remote box and locate the file you want to edit. So
you google how to edit it and you discover this program valled &ldquo;Vim&rdquo;.
Excited to use this new program you type in vim filename.ext and it opens up
the file and you see the content. &ldquo;Yay!!&rdquo; you say to yourself. Then you attempt
to use the mouse to go to where you want to edit and click.. &ldquo;Hmm.. it&rsquo;s not
working..&rdquo; then you try to type in some letters to make sure you can at least do
that. click click click.. &ldquo;That&rsquo;s not working either! what is wrong with this
program!!&rdquo;. Shortly after this frustration you realize that you can use the
arrow keys to move around and after a quick google you can insert text after
clicking &lsquo;i&rsquo;. At this point you can move around and edit files but you&rsquo;re having
a terrible time. &ldquo;THIS EDITOR SUCKS&rdquo; you say to yourself.
</span></p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t worry, we&#8217;e all been there. I would venture to say no one likes Vim the
first time they open it up.</p>

<blockquote><p>Here is my current monster of a .vimrc</p><footer><strong>@jakecraige</strong> <cite><a href='https://gist.github.com/jakecraige/6236660'>gist.github.com/jakecraige/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>Yikes! That&rsquo;s pretty scary! I agree, when you first lay eyes on this it looks to
be pretty wild. Though it&rsquo;s really not so bad when you start to
look through it. It&rsquo;s only a collection of alias&rsquo;s for different commands
to make life easier. While vim is powerful at it&rsquo;s basic level, adding in plugins
and custom aliases is where it really starts to shine. <em>And hey, I&rsquo;ve organized
it into folds for easy navigation.</em></p>

<h2>My Vim Journey</h2>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Slowly but surely I continued to improve until
I didn&#8217;t really want to use Sublime Text anymore. I actually had more typos in
it from hitting my Vim binds in it.'>
I had messed around with Vim a few times throughout the years and always
switched back to using a modern text editor like Sublime Text 2. It just seemed
easier, and yeah, it was, but that doesn&rsquo;t mean it was the best solution for me.
About 3 or 4 months ago I read lots of articles and setup a vimrc and began to
actively using vim as my primary text editor. At work I still used Sublime Text
2 so as to not slow me down, and at home I would use Vim and continued to get
better. After a few weeks I felt pretty confident in using it and set it up on
the computer at work as well. Slowly but surely I continued to improve until
I didn&rsquo;t really want to use Sublime Text anymore. I actually had more typos in
it from hitting my Vim binds in it. It starts to become muscle memory after
awhile and you just can&rsquo;t stop. You just get that itch to hit &rsquo;ll the time!!
(more on that later) I am constantly updating my vimrc with new things that
would be helpful and have completely changed it multiple times throughout this
experience. At first I was using spf13&rsquo;s vim setup and that was good for awhile
but seemed to run slower than I wanted it to and included things I didn&rsquo;t want
to use so I got rid of it. Now I have a complete custom vimrc (lots stolen from
others) but one that I have put together so it works best for me. It takes time
to get to learn to use Vim but I think it&rsquo;s worth it.
</span></p>

<h2>Now that I&rsquo;ve scared you a bit. Let&rsquo;s get to it!</h2>

<p>First step, open up terminal and type in &lsquo;vimtutor&rsquo;.(minus the quotes). Run
through that tutorial to get a basic understanding of how to move around the
file and edit things. That alone will help you start to see some of it&rsquo;s power.
I haven&rsquo;t used this site, but it seems very similar to vimtutor but a bit more
interactive so you could give it a shot as well
<a href="http://www.openvim.com/tutorial.html.">http://www.openvim.com/tutorial.html.</a></p>

<p>After that it&rsquo;s time to start setting up a vimrc.</p>

<p>Ugh. I&rsquo;ll continue this later. If anyone comes upon it before then, these helped
me get started.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://stevelosh.com/blog/2010/09/coming-home-to-vim/">http://stevelosh.com/blog/2010/09/coming-home-to-vim/</a></li>
<li><a href="http://net.tutsplus.com/articles/general/top-10-pitfalls-when-switching-to-vim/">http://net.tutsplus.com/articles/general/top-10-pitfalls-when-switching-to-vim/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/spf13/spf13-vim">https://github.com/spf13/spf13-vim</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New blog yay]]></title>
    <link href="http://jakecraige.github.io/blog/2013/08/14/new-blog-yay/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-14T17:07:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jakecraige.github.io/blog/2013/08/14/new-blog-yay</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Hey there!</em> I am testing some stuff.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>Fake test class</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="k">class</span> <span class="nc">Test</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">hey</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="n">hey</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">end</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">end</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>`</p>

<blockquote><p>And heeerreee. Is a gist!</p><footer><strong>Jake Craige</strong> <cite>His Playful Self</cite></footer></blockquote>




<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/6227391.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code></code></pre></noscript></div>




<figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='php'><span class='line'><span class="k">echo</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Well this is all about them tests!&quot;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='I am magic'>
Well i don&rsquo;t really have anything to write here but i wanted to use the
pullquote as they request of me. I am magic I told them. But no one
believed me. It was so sad that this happend like that. Well, I&rsquo;m excited about
this new blog. Yay ruby and rails? hah. DUHH yay!
</span></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
